Igor Rodin

Email: <u>i.rod1245@gmail.com</u> Phone: +7 999 735 99 92

About Me

A Senior Frontend Engineer with strong analytics experience. My motivation loop: learn the problem, take ownership, make things done, analyze impact. Working with a passion for details and the best user experience. Openminded, proactive and focused on delivering results.

Languages/Frameworks

Expert in JavaScript, React, and Redux Confident in VueJS Proficient in Python, PHP, SQL, Django, and Laravel

Work experience

HubHaus, Growth Engineer / Full Stack Engineer (10/2018 - present)

VueJS universal app architecture + CI/CD configuration (VueJS, Docker, AWS ECS)

Designed and created a VueJS project generator with preconfigured internal packages including authentication and a UI toolkit. Prepared npm packages for generator.

Web scraping platform (Python, Scrapy, AWS FireHose)

Designed and created a platform for continuous web scraping. The platform provides an infrastructure for creating scrapers, monitoring their progress and measuring data loss.

AWS SageMaker model CI/CD (Docker, Python, AWS ECS)

Dockerized an ML model, created an API wrapper, set up an infrastructure for deployment, and integrated a UI to interact with the model.

ergeon, Senior Full Stack Engineer (05/2018 - 10/2018)

Frontend projects migration (React, React SSR, Redux)

ergeon bought the ezhome codebase. Cleaned up and refactored the frontend app for a new product.

ezhome, Senior Frontend Engineer / Architect / Frontend Lead (09/2015 - 05/2018)

A/B test platform and analytics integration for customer-facing apps (Segment, Google Analytics, Mixpanel, Google Optimize)

Project lead for analytics integration. Developed naming conventions and event data structures. Guided mobile engineers with implementation and reviewed all platform integration results. Interacted with data engineers to receive requirements and feedback for analytics data. Implemented and integrated cross-project A/B testing platform.

React universal app architecture (React, React SSR, Redux)

Early proponent of universal (isomorphic) app architecture. Developed React-based SSR architecture, discovered and fixed many cross-platform problems. Led frontend team to develop apps based on that architecture.

Kibbit, Senior Frontend Developer / Architect (01/2015 - 09/2015)

AngularJS frontend architecture (AngularJS 1.x)

Created an AngularJS app architecture. Led frontend development.

Hotelbook service, Senior Frontend Developer / Architect (06/2014 - 01/2015)

Flocktory, Senior Developer, Internal Interfaces (12/2013 - 06/2014)

LinguaLeo, JavaScript Developer (08/2012 - 11/2013)

Education

09/2010 – 01/2012 Cisco Networking Academy, Obninsk, Kaluga region, Russia 09/2010 – 06/2012 Master's degree specializing in Information Technology

Scientific Research Nuclear University MEPhl, Faculty of Cybernetics

Obninsk, Kaluga region, Russia

09/2006 - 07/2010 Bachelor's degree specializing in Computer Systems, Networks and Technologies

Scientific Research Nuclear University MEPhl, Faculty of Cybernetics

Obninsk, Kaluga region, Russia

Personality

Strengths

Spatial thinking

• Ability to see from another person's point of view and approach situations from different perspectives.

Approach to work

- Be flexible, be detail-oriented, and think long term. Always find the right balance between speed and quality.
- Be passionate about what you are doing and think about the product as a whole.
- See task/decisions/roadmap from a business/product owner's perspective. Always try to understand other points of view.
- Having a well-thought-through architecture is the key to success.
- QA and delivering high-quality products is important.

Personal Interests

Rock-climbing (was a coach for rock-climbing university team), downhill, cycling